<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Barry Hikes The PCT</title><link href="http://www.barryhikesthepct.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.barryhikesthepct.com/feeds/pct.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.barryhikesthepct.com/</id><updated>2015-06-12T00:00:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>Day 41 - 8.7 miles from Manter Creek to Kennedy Meadows (Mile 702.4)</title><link href="http://www.barryhikesthepct.com/day-41-87-miles-from-manter-creek-to-kennedy-meadows-mile-7024.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-06-12T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Barry Wainstock</name></author><id>tag:www.barryhikesthepct.com,2015-06-12:day-41-87-miles-from-manter-creek-to-kennedy-meadows-mile-7024.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/eaYNYym.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/eaYNYym.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After two full days back on trail, I
slept really well and woke excited. Kennedy Meadows was in our sights and we should be there by 10 o'clock. Within the first mile, we could see open meadows on horizon. 
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/PefAmPt.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/PefAmPt.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Today took us through easy rolling sandy hills to the south fork of the Kern River where we stopped for snacks. We didn't need water so kept hiking after a short break. The trail finally hit the meadows and our pace picked up. Large peaks and pine trees filled the horizon and we finally passed mile 700. 
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/3PTvZBh.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/3PTvZBh.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
The final 2.4 miles were a blur and we walked directly to the Kennedy Meadows General Store due a hamburger and soda. About 40 other hikers were here building up the strength to start their journey into the mountains. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll stay the night here, pickup our food resupply, and pack our bear cans. The Sierra mountains require bear proof cans for all of your food. This adds an extra two pounds to the backpack and will take some getting used to. &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Day 40 - 20.8 miles from mile 672.9 to Manter Creek (Mile 693.7)</title><link href="http://www.barryhikesthepct.com/day-40-208-miles-from-mile-6729-to-manter-creek-mile-6937.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-06-11T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Barry Wainstock</name></author><id>tag:www.barryhikesthepct.com,2015-06-11:day-40-208-miles-from-mile-6729-to-manter-creek-mile-6937.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/3QGB9IZ.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/3QGB9IZ.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today started with a nice change of pace. We were starting by descending instead of climbing a giant hill. The morning was overcast, but still warm. The first goal was a campground about eight miles out where we'd fill water from a spigot and eat a snack. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we got to the campground entrance, there was a sign saying the spigot was on the far end, over a mile away! Thankfully Chimney Creek was nearby and we decided to break there instead.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/kiTTjQq.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/kiTTjQq.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
We met hikers new to us Crunchberry and Stayin Alive here and ate snacks. After filling our water bottles, we left around 11 o'clock to start a 2400 foot climb. The trail was more coarse desert sand with gentle shade. About five miles in, we stopped under a large oak tree with low branches for lunch and a quick nap. 
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/3w3AObJ.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/3w3AObJ.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
We finished our final hour of climbing and descended the other side of the hill.  Sparse trees turned into a burn area and our shade disappeared. After the first few miles, the sand turned into ankle twisting granite rocks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The day finally finished at the nicely flowing Manter Creek. We got to camp early enough that we could rinse our feet and wipe the day's dust off of our legs.  There are a lot of other campers at this site as we're only a short eight miles from Kennedy Meadows. This is a major milestone and the entrance to the Sierra.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow we'll finish those last eight miles and prepare ourselves for the climb into the mountains. &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Day 39 - 21.5 miles from Walker Pass to mile 672.9</title><link href="http://www.barryhikesthepct.com/day-39-215-miles-from-walker-pass-to-mile-6729.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-06-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Barry Wainstock</name></author><id>tag:www.barryhikesthepct.com,2015-06-10:day-39-215-miles-from-walker-pass-to-mile-6729.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/w5oxTSC.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/w5oxTSC.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After what felt like a long, but needed break from hiking, we're finally back on trail. Our friend Frankenstein drove from Orange County to pick us up and take us back to Walker Pass. An uneventful drive down I5 took us to the campground where we ate dinner and camped one last time with Frankenstein. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Waking up in the morning, we noticed there were about 15 other hikers camped out. This brought us right back into the hiking mindset and we quickly packed up and got ready to go. We said goodbye to Frankenstein and thanked him over and over before finally heading back out to hike. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first eight miles took us up a 2300 foot climb into the Owens Peak Wilderness. Sandy hills patched with tufts of golden grass turned into trees as we climbed. Swarms of grasshoppers in the trees buzzed like tazers as they fluttered around us. 
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/WZ7VK8H.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/WZ7VK8H.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
A few miles down the other side of the mountain we stopped at Joshua Tree spring for water. The hikers that were already there told us they had just chased away a bear also getting water. We decided to chance it and headed down to the spring. If the threat of a bear wasn't going to stop is, nor was the sign warning us about uranium. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ate lunch in the shade and napped for two hours through the midday heat. As we woke, more hikers filtered in and we decided it was time to leave. Just as we were headed out, the bear came back for another drink. We turned around just to get a glimpse and quickly left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The day finished as it had started with a 2000 don't climb over the last five miles. Part way up the climb we passed the quarter mark of the trail. The path was shaded, but covered in granite shards which made for a slow hike. The scenery felt like we were finally getting to the Sierra. 
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/GoSrkTC.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/GoSrkTC.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
We will try to put in another full day tomorrow leaving just a few more miles afterwards to get into Kennedy Meadows. Then we'll really be entering the next phase of the trail. &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Day 38 - 13.4 miles from mile 638 to Walker Pass Campground (Mile 651.4)</title><link href="http://www.barryhikesthepct.com/day-38-134-miles-from-mile-638-to-walker-pass-campground-mile-6514.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Barry Wainstock</name></author><id>tag:www.barryhikesthepct.com,2015-05-28:day-38-134-miles-from-mile-638-to-walker-pass-campground-mile-6514.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/77Jipwb.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title="Our hiking bubble at Walker Pass Campground before we left the trail (Hornbuckle, Junior, me, Matt, Starfish, Honeystick, Andy, Bird, Wendybird, and Mowgli)"&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/77Jipwb.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;div class="image-caption"&gt;
        Our hiking bubble at Walker Pass Campground before we left the trail (Hornbuckle, Junior, me, Matt, Starfish, Honeystick, Andy, Bird, Wendybird, and Mowgli)
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our original plan for the day was slightly interrupted by the heat. After a fairly quick and easy 13 miles downhill into Walker Pass, we met Matt's mom for our planned resupply. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along with her and her van, there was a silver Airstream with a popup tent and tables offering hikers soda and fruit. The tables were packed with hikers new and old and we took a minute to say hi before sitting down with Jan and eating lunch. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of lunch, the three of us were feeling less than motivated to hike out and the heat of the day had reached its peak. After a quick assessment of our injuries, we decided we'd get off trail two days early and enjoy some extra downtime. Jan had already booked herself a hotel in nearby Kernville so we followed suit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The revised plan is to get off trail two days early and return to Walker Pass after our break. We said our goodbyes to the friends we've made in the past month and will rejoin the trail in about two weeks. &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Day 37 - 21.3 miles from mile 617.7 to mile 638</title><link href="http://www.barryhikesthepct.com/day-37-213-miles-from-mile-6177-to-mile-638.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-27T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Barry Wainstock</name></author><id>tag:www.barryhikesthepct.com,2015-05-27:day-37-213-miles-from-mile-6177-to-mile-638.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/Efq7Vj8.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/Efq7Vj8.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After more than 600 miles of fairly gentle desert, we were finally hitting unrelenting dry terrain. We planned for another early morning because of the heat and got started on our hike up and over the first set of hills. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kale had warned us the other day that this part of the trail would be frustrating. The climb wasn't all that bad, climbing less than 1000 feet over two miles and then flattening out for the next four. The issue came from the never ending sand. It felt like trying to hike uphill on the beach. It felt very much like one step forward, two steps back. Together with the already sweltering heat, this morning sapped our energy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By midday we had made it to mile 631 at Bird Spring Pass. We had heard there was a water cache here and we came to find multiple jugs of water and lounge chairs. There were plenty of hikers waiting out the heat here and we gladly joined them. While Bird and I napped in the shade, Matt pushed on and climbed the 1500 feet out of the pass. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After our two hour nap, Bird and I followed Matt up the mountain. It turns out two hours wasn't quite long enough and the sun was still blistering hot. The climb was arduous and it felt like it took forever. 
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/tYyz4kY.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/tYyz4kY.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Halfway up the climb we met a man out for a day hike going the opposite way as us. He told us we were the 52nd and 53rd people he'd seen that day. I had never really thought about what it was like outside of our bubble of hikers. Five miles ahead of us was a completely different group of people hiking at the same speed as is and we'd never see them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shortly after the peak of the climb, we found Matt taking his turn in the shade and we took a sidetrail to Yellow Jacket Spring. This spring was referred to as a seep and was more of a refilling puddle than a flowing stream. We dipped our bottles in the puddle and waited in the shade a bit longer. 
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/mNT7d2M.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/mNT7d2M.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
This was the first time we had cell phone service in a long time. Matt took the opportunity to call his mother to coordinate our pickup from Kennedy Meadows. We are all getting off trail to go to a friend's wedding. Along with picking us up in Kennedy Meadows, Jan is going to drop us off a food resupply tomorrow in Walker Pass. This will save us from having to hitch 45 minutes each way into Onyx. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the phone call, we continued about one mile farther and setup camp in the middle of some oak trees. We were once again exhausted and quickly setup camp. Tomorrow will see us hiking into Walker Pass and right back out on our way to Kennedy Meadows. We'd like to be there around lunch so we'll have another early morning.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Day 36 - 27.7 miles from mile 588.2 to Kelso Road (Mile 615.9)</title><link href="http://www.barryhikesthepct.com/day-36-277-miles-from-mile-5882-to-kelso-road-mile-6159.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Barry Wainstock</name></author><id>tag:www.barryhikesthepct.com,2015-05-26:day-36-277-miles-from-mile-5882-to-kelso-road-mile-6159.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/fpqLcjG.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/fpqLcjG.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We woke up early this morning hoping to get a jump on the heat.  We were pretty tired yesterday, partially from it being our first day out of town and partially from the heat.  The first couple miles finished the barren burn zone that we ended with yesterday.  From there we climbed through meadowed hillsides into a wonderful pine forest.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/knbSYEx.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/knbSYEx.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/8bt9b87.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/8bt9b87.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Most of the day was spent in the forest studded with large granite rocks.  It felt like we were getting ever closer to the Sierra Mountains.  Around midday we came upon small water cache about quarter mile before our first expected water source and decided to stop for lunch and naps. Honey Stick, Kale, and Mowgli joined us in the shade and we left after a relaxing 90 minute break.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/KEOTKvm.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/KEOTKvm.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
The hike continued along a gentle trail through oaks and skinny pine trees to our next water source near Landers Camp.  Andy, Mowgli, and Honey Stick hung out with us for a while as we ate more and filtered water before pushing on for the final miles of the day.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/MjMagPZ.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/MjMagPZ.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
The end of the day took us through a white sandy burn zone littered with purple and yellow flowers. By the end of the hike, we were all pretty exhausted and setup camp on the side of a dirt road.  The wind was blowing through the desert again and cars periodically drove passed.  Our campsite had an expansive view of the sunset though, which made the night much more bearable.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Day 35 - 21.7 miles from Highway 58 to mile 588.2</title><link href="http://www.barryhikesthepct.com/day-35-217-miles-from-highway-58-to-mile-5882.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Barry Wainstock</name></author><id>tag:www.barryhikesthepct.com,2015-05-25:day-35-217-miles-from-highway-58-to-mile-5882.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/W82lrfo.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/W82lrfo.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This morning the breakfast room was filled with even more hikers than yesterday.  Purple Princess, Dunzo, Honey Stick, Starfish, Junior, and plenty more were around.  Unfortunately, when we tried Big Al for a ride, he didn't answer.  There were plenty more trail angels in town, however, and we were able to get to the trailhead by 9AM.  It was already hot outside and we found Liability, Sticky Buns, and Dreaded Mustache setting off right in front of us. 
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/Trl8JuX.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/Trl8JuX.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
After about a mile of flat trail, we climbed 2000 feet into the Tehachapi Mountains through coarse sand.  The hot, sandy hills coupled with a fresh, heavy resupply and 6 liters of water meant slow going this morning. Once we made it into the mountains, the temperature cooled off and we had a bit more tree cover.  We walked along a tree lined dirt road for most of the morning until we stopped under a large oak tree for lunch.  Kale, Liability, Dreaded Milkshake, and Sticky Buns joined us while I napped through the early afternoon heat.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/GNmehFq.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/GNmehFq.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Around 2:30PM, we left our lunch spot and hiked through the rocky, high desert hills.  We reached our water supply for the day around 5 o'clock and found a large group of hikers huddled around.  The source was basically a cow trough so the quality wasn't the highest.  While sitting around filtering, a few cows stopped by to take their fill.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/xXbTQQI.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/xXbTQQI.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/DQ5ef44.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/DQ5ef44.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
About five more miles of hiking through another burn zone saw us to our final destination: a makeshift campsite in a small ravine.  We plan to hike close to thirty miles tomorrow with the hope of getting into Kennedy Meadows sooner than later.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Day 34 - 8 mile slack pack from Highway 58 to Willow Springs Road (Mile 566.5)</title><link href="http://www.barryhikesthepct.com/day-34-8-mile-slack-pack-from-highway-58-to-willow-springs-road-mile-5665.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Barry Wainstock</name></author><id>tag:www.barryhikesthepct.com,2015-05-24:day-34-8-mile-slack-pack-from-highway-58-to-willow-springs-road-mile-5665.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/oFEPegd.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/oFEPegd.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a big breakfast with Crash, Big Ups, and a few other hikers in the hotel's breakfast room, we called Big Al for a ride to the trail head.  Geared up with only a few snacks and water, we were excited to fly through the trail today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big Al told us it would be easier to get picked up from Willow Springs Road at mile 558.5 instead of from our original finishing point for the day, so we decided to hike backwards for this section.  Big Al dropped us off at the highway near mile 566.5 and we got to walking.  The trail was very similar to the last few days with sand under our feet and desert shrubs speckling the hillsides.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With little weight on our backs, we flew up the 1000 foot climb.  A fellow hiker, Kale, was doing the same thing as us today, but in reverse.  We caught him just as he was finishing the hill and he told us his parents were picking him up from the highway.  Kale assured us that the rest of the trail was fairly flat and we would have no problems for the rest of the hike.  The hill was also the first time we'd seen horses on the trail.  The whole trail is supposed to be graded for horses and we've seen evidence of horse use, but this was the first time we've seen the actual animals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rest of the hike was uneventful and we made it to the road within a few hours.  While waiting once again for Big Al to pick us up, we chatted with a few locals out for a run on the PCT.  Running Deer and his friends were very excited that we were out hiking and reminded us, no matter the circumstances of the day, to enjoy the music of the wilderness.  Even though the wind could be pretty frustrating in this section, the sounds it made were quite beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After our slackpack, our town day was pretty standard.  We resupplied our food bags, ate lunch, finished laundry, and watched another movie.  We met up with Tater, Darko, and a couple of their friends for pizza and called it a night.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow starts the hike into Kennedy Meadows which means the unofficial end of the desert.  Unfortunately, this last stretch is looking to be pretty warm and doesn't have a lot of water, which means heavy carries.  We'll eat another breakfast at the hotel tomorrow morning and call Big Al for one more ride.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Day 33 - 8.9 miles from mile 549.6 to Willow Springs Road into Tehachapi (Mile 558.5)</title><link href="http://www.barryhikesthepct.com/day-33-89-miles-from-mile-5496-to-willow-springs-road-into-tehachapi-mile-5585.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Barry Wainstock</name></author><id>tag:www.barryhikesthepct.com,2015-05-23:day-33-89-miles-from-mile-5496-to-willow-springs-road-into-tehachapi-mile-5585.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/WksLnfQ.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/WksLnfQ.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We planned yesterday's long hike so that today would be quick and painless.  The 9 miles we hiked today were mostly downhill and we got an early enough start that the weather wasn't too warm.  Other than still hiking through a massive wind farm, our plan worked out and we made it to Willow Springs Road by 10AM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once we got to the road, we found a long list of trail angels posted and quickly gave the number next to Big Al's name a call.  While waiting for Big Al to come pick us up, we booked a room at the Best Western and chatted with Hornbuckle and Wind Screen as they waited for a hitch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big Al picked us up within 15 minutes and drove us into Tehachapi.  It seemed like his whole day was planned around giving hikers rides.  Big Al offered to take us to the post office and pick us up when we were done to drop us off at our hotel.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After finishing up our business at the post office, we headed to the hotel and got to work on our standard town chores.  Showers, naps, and food were all standards.  We walked off our town lunch and stopped into the Tehachapi Museum to see what the local history was all about.  Mary, the museum steward, showed us pictures from her backyard of California Condor chicks and gigantic elk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tehachapi also has a movie theater so we decided we would spend the evening watching the new Mad Max.  About two minutes in my body decided I needed more sleep and I missed most the movie.  We finished the night off with delicious BBQ and got to bed early.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're staying in town another full day tomorrow.  The next 8 or so miles of the trail continue through the wind farm and don't have any water sources.  We're planning to call Big Al again for a ride to the trail and slackpacking this section.  Slackpacking means leaving most of your pack in town or with a trail angel and only taking minimal weight.  We should be able to fly through these 8 miles and get back to town for more rest.  We still need to resupply our food and do laundry.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Day 32 - 32 miles from Hiker Town to mile 549.6</title><link href="http://www.barryhikesthepct.com/day-32-32-miles-from-hiker-town-to-mile-5496.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Barry Wainstock</name></author><id>tag:www.barryhikesthepct.com,2015-05-22:day-32-32-miles-from-hiker-town-to-mile-5496.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/mqPGqWz.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/mqPGqWz.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a decent night's sleep in a real bed in Hiker Town, we were on the trail by 5:45AM with 32 miles ahead of us.  The first 18 or so miles along the Aqueduct were flat and easy.  We were expected boring as well, but the sunrise and views across the Mojave Desert provided for a great hike.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/PuoR0xS.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/PuoR0xS.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
While Bird and I stopped periodically to snack or catch our breath, Matt powered through the morning all the way to the first water stop 17 miles in.  Bird and I stopped here around 11:45 for lunch just as Matt was leaving.  He'd already been there for close to an hour.  This was the last we saw of him until camp later at night.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/NeFcSe8.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/NeFcSe8.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
The water was at the start of the PCT famous wind farm and we could already tell the end of the day was going to be more difficult than the beginning.  Gusting winds slowed our hike down considerably and the clouds hanging over the desert mountains misted on us periodically.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along with the wind, we were climbing into the desert hills away from the flat desert floor.  Our first stop in the hills was Tylerhorse Canyon where we intended to refill our water again.  Where we expected a strong flowing creek, we found a trickle of water which we had to scoop using our pots to get it into our water bottles.  After a short break here with Taxi and Hornbuckle, we continued on through the hills.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/4XIsfGm.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/4XIsfGm.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
By now, we were both pretty tired and the climbs were getting harder.  The wind was still gusting and the trail was sandy, which made every step harder than the last.  We passed a big campsite about a quarter mile before our intended stopping point and said "Hi" to our friends Doogan and Sweetums.  Thankfully, the last quarter mile was downhill and we finally reached camp, 32 miles farther than we were this morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were hoping that this side of the hill would be out of the wind, but no luck tonight.  We're camped between bushes which should help a bit, but tonight will be a tough night to sleep through.  Tomorrow leaves us with 8 miles into Tehachapi where we'll have a motel room to sleep and shower and do laundry.  We'll take a zero day in Tehachapi as well, so we can catch up on any rest we don't get tonight.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Day 31 - Nero from Casa De Luna to Hiker Town (Mile 517.6)</title><link href="http://www.barryhikesthepct.com/day-31-nero-from-casa-de-luna-to-hiker-town-mile-5176.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Barry Wainstock</name></author><id>tag:www.barryhikesthepct.com,2015-05-21:day-31-nero-from-casa-de-luna-to-hiker-town-mile-5176.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/3onfKiB.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/3onfKiB.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We didn't get our hitch in time.  That tells most of the story of the day.  After a nice pancake breakfast at The Anderson's, Terri drove us back to the road where we were to hitch.  Since most of the cars on the rode were morning commuters, getting a ride was pretty tough and we walked along for about 5 miles.  Eventually, we were picked up by a nice guy in a pickup truck and he took us as far as The Historic Rock Inn in Lake Hughes.  We stopped in around 10AM to eat a second breakfast and to figure out what our options were with fellow hiker Hornbuckle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Option 1&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Walk 12 miles from The Rock Inn to Hiker Town along the road&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Option 2&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Walk four miles along the road to the end of the fire closure and walk 22 miles of trail to Hiker Town &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Option 3&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hitch the four miles to the end of the fire closure and walk 22 miles of trail to Hiker Town&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Option 4&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hitch all the way into Hiker Town&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both Bird and I really dislike road walking as it's typically boring, dangerous, and hard on the knees.  Hornbuckle and Matt didn't mind the road walk and didn't particularly want to walk the full 20 plus miles to Hiker Town.  Bird and I decided we'd try to walk to trail if we could get a hitch in time, but that we'd hitch all the way to Hiker Town if we couldn't.  Hornbuckle and Matt decided to just road walk into Hiker Town.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Bird and I left the restaurant, we walked along the road with our thumbs out with our friend Liability trailing behind us about 100 yards.  We didn't have much luck for the first hour or so and continued walking.  Our trail walking deadline passed and we resigned to just hitching directly into Hiker Town.  This would give us another easy day to sort out further logistics.  Bird needed to buy new shoes and I planned to update my blog since I'd been slacking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A nice man named Steve, who worked at the Christian camp in town, picked us up on his way to an appointment.  He told us he would have to stop at his appointment for about an hour, but if we stayed on the road, he'd pick us back up and take us where we needed to go.  Liability gave us his backpack to take with us which made his road walk much easier.  When Steve dropped us off to go to his appointment, we left our bags in his car and kept walking down the road.  This made for a rather enjoyable, leisurely walk along the highway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By about 1 o'clock, Steve had picked us back up and we reached Hiker Town.  This property was the work of an eccentric man who built a replica Western town out of old movie set pieces.  The garage had been converted into a hiker lounge with laundry, showers, and couches to sit around on.  Small shacks and shipping containers surrounded the property for hikers to sleep in and there were spots to camp if we wanted to.  We decided to rent out one of the small rooms and had a generally lazy afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mad Science was in the garage lounge when we got there and it was nice to catch up with him.  Later in the day, most of the hikers we'd seen at the Anderson's trickled into Hiker Town and we all ate and drank together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow we hike 18 flat miles along the California Aqueduct.  Most of the hikers here plan to put in 30 or more miles to make the next day relatively short into Tehachapi.  We've got 32 miles planned in our minds which means a 5:30AM departure time. &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Day 30 - 25.7 miles from Vasquez Rocks to Casa De Luna (Mile 478.6)</title><link href="http://www.barryhikesthepct.com/day-30-257-miles-from-vasquez-rocks-to-casa-de-luna-mile-4786.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Barry Wainstock</name></author><id>tag:www.barryhikesthepct.com,2015-05-20:day-30-257-miles-from-vasquez-rocks-to-casa-de-luna-mile-4786.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/HaFCzLs.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/HaFCzLs.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out of Vasquez Rocks picnic area and through the town of Agua Dulce a little over an hour.  The trail actually turns into the road through town for a few miles which made hiking fairly fast.  From town we climbed 2000 feet back into the hills of the Angeles National Forest.  We were surrounded by green hillsides in every direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday's short hike and early night left me feeling energized.  A minor milestone for thru-hikers is hitting 10 miles by 10AM and we got to our first water source at the 10.5 mile mark just before 10AM.  After a break for water and second/third breakfast, we continued our walk through the lush green hills.  The terrain wasn't particularly exciting, but it was a nice day with easy hiking.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/UJt4Khq.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/UJt4Khq.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
The quick morning meant we got to our final destination around 5 o'clock.  We had passed a man out for a run within the last couple of miles of our hike and he came back to the trailhead as we were trying to hitch into Casa De Luna.  He waved us over to his car and told us he knew exactly where we were going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We pulled up to Casa De Luna shortly after getting picked up and the driver walked right over to Joe and Terrie Anderson, the trail angels that lived here.  Apparently everyone in this small town knows each other.  The Anderson's provide camping in their manzanita forest backyard, showers, charging stations, beer, and best of all, dinner and breakfast.  We quickly found a spot in the forest to setup camp and headed back out to hang with the rest of the hikers.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/e9ynTeH.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/e9ynTeH.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
We met a southbound hiker who was finishing the trail in sections named GoalTech and a large group of hikers we already knew were sitting around the front yard chatting.  Starfish, Wendy Bird, Junior, Honey Stick, Velcro, FM, Andy, Vince, and all sorts of other hikers were drinking and laughing and soaking in the good vibes.  This is a great stop along the trail and a fantastic place to forget about some of the aches and pains of the trail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It'll be hard to leave, but tomorrow we've got to get out of The Anderson's early.  Breakfast is at 6:30 and we plan to leave shortly after.  There is another fire closure on the trail ahead and we plan to hitchhike around it.  If we can get a hitch in time, we hope to walk about 24 miles to our final destination, Hiker Town.  If we can't get a hitch in time, we'll just hitchhike all the way to Hiker Town and miss the 500 mile marker.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Day 29 - 8.6 miles from Acton KOA to Vasquez Rocks (Mile 452.9)</title><link href="http://www.barryhikesthepct.com/day-29-86-miles-from-acton-koa-to-vasquez-rocks-mile-4529.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Barry Wainstock</name></author><id>tag:www.barryhikesthepct.com,2015-05-19:day-29-86-miles-from-acton-koa-to-vasquez-rocks-mile-4529.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/Qb2kJrS.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/Qb2kJrS.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leaving the Acton KOA was slow going.  Sleeping on nice green grass and having reliable WiFi made it hard to get walking.  Eventually we got our gear packed up and we were on the road.  We had yet another hill to climb this morning and then we'd drop down into Vasquez Rocks.  While on top of the hill, I called a trail angel to see if she could help settle my trekking poles.  Mary amazingly offered to pick us up at Vasquez Rocks and take us into Palmdale to a sporting goods store.  She told us we'd be able to resupply our food there as well.  Both Matt and Bird were on board with the plan and we decided our hike would end at Vasquez Rocks.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/TSFBMMx.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/TSFBMMx.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
We got to Vasquez Rocks around noon and Mary pulled up shortly after to take us into town.  She gave us a three hour window to get our chores done and we took the opportunity to stuff our stomachs at the Asian buffet.  I was able to fix my trekking pole situation at the Sport Chalet and we resupplied at Smart and Final.  All of these stores were in one giant shopping center which was a bit overwhelming.  There were town people everywhere and smells bombarded us everwhere.  We weren't used to so many perfumes and deodorants.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/dl2NWbU.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/dl2NWbU.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Mary dropped us back off at Vasquez Rocks and we watched as our hiking buddies passed through.  The last of the hikers came by our camp around 6 o'clock as the rest timed their arrival in town with the opening of the market.  An easy hiking day lead to a pretty lazy evening and we watched the sunset through the huge, sharp rock formations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because we don't need to resupply in Agua Dulce anymore, we plan to not stop in town and hike straight through.  The goal for tomorrow is another trail angel house: Casa de Luna!&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Day 28 - 25.7 miles from Mill Creek Fire Station to Acton KOA (Mile 444.3)</title><link href="http://www.barryhikesthepct.com/day-28-257-miles-from-mill-creek-fire-station-to-acton-koa-mile-4443.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-18T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Barry Wainstock</name></author><id>tag:www.barryhikesthepct.com,2015-05-18:day-28-257-miles-from-mill-creek-fire-station-to-acton-koa-mile-4443.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/ZJgM5iv.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/ZJgM5iv.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another big mileage day meant another early start.  Apparently a massive cloud had settled on our tents last night and left our tents soaking wet.  We'd have to find a place to dry them out when the sun was high around lunchtime.  And of course an early start somehow means climbing a mountain first thing in the morning.  We kicked the day off by climbing 1500 feet back into the Angeles National Forest through more poodle dog bush.  This vicious plant was everywhere and really hard to dodge, making the morning very frustrating.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just passed the top of climb we stopped to eat lunch and dry our gear at Messenger Flat campground around 5500 ft elevation.  Somehow we ended up picking the shadiest, windiest spot to stop and we ate quickly before we got too cold.  We continued down mountain and stopped again around 4200 feet at the North Fork Ranger Station to refill water and rest our feet. The last eight miles of the day would be all downhill and we were dreading what it would do to our knees.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/55s4gZp.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/55s4gZp.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
After eating more food and meeting fellow hikers String Bean and FM at the ranger station, we climbed all the way down the trail to the Acton KOA campground at 2200 feet.  Chaparral hills turned into white sand with red clay hillsides in the distance.  Somewhere on the descent, I broke both of my trekking pole tips.  Luckily, there is a trail angel in Agua Dulce that should be able to help me get new poles.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tonight, the KOA has a hot tub, showers, laundry and we ordered pizza to be delivered directly to our tent.  Crash and his friend Big Ups are staying here tonight as well.  Tomorrow we'll hike into the small town of Agua Dulce to resupply our food bags and hike right back out.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Day 27 - 27.3 miles from mile 394 to Mill Creek Fire Station (Mile 418.6)</title><link href="http://www.barryhikesthepct.com/day-27-273-miles-from-mile-394-to-mill-creek-fire-station-mile-4186.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Barry Wainstock</name></author><id>tag:www.barryhikesthepct.com,2015-05-17:day-27-273-miles-from-mile-394-to-mill-creek-fire-station-mile-4186.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/EET8m17.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/EET8m17.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cold evening left frost on the outside of our tents and gave us a reason to break camp quickly to build up some body heat this morning.  We had to take a 2.7 mile side trail out of the campground down into Cooper Canyon.  The trail was chilly, but covered in soft, healthy soil and lined with vibrant green foliage.  Just as we descended into the canyon, we climbed right back out and crossed Highway 2 three times. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we stopped for a snack break at the first crossing, we noticed a trail angel on the other side of the road handing out goodies. The trail angel had driven from near LAX airport to give out less obvious supplies like Chapstick, hot sauce, first aid supplies, and Spam. After a nice 45 minute break we continued down through the San Gabriel Mountains and passed mile 400.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/XEGP0Bz.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/XEGP0Bz.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
At mile 402 we passed a nonprofit Boy Scout Camp called Camp Glenwood.  Initially, we had planned to refill our water here and move on.  However, just as we were setting our bags down, one of the caretakers, Max, was firing up his grill to cook hamburgers and invited us to stay for lunch.  This lead to another hour long break where we chatted about the drivers on Highway 2 and the car wreckage you can find throughout the hills from corners being taken too tightly. We thanked Max for his kindness and kept climbing down through miles of poodle dog bush.  We hit more trail magic around noon: hot dogs and fruit!  Apparently weekends in Angeles National Forest are a good time for city folk to help out hungry hikers.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/lkPZB35.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/lkPZB35.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Later in the day we climbed up 1500 feet and back down 1500 feet to Mill Creek Fire Station.  The trail was windy, but well covered and never got too hot.  We showed up to a windy picnic area around 7 and setup camp next to about 10 other hikers. Because of the wind, we ate dinner in front of the concrete bathrooms and chatted with an Australian hiker named Crash.  Soon after dinner we climbed into our tents and quickly fell asleep.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today was our first marathon day feel and we felt it.  Tomorrow we're hoping to put in another big mile day.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Day 26 - 24.6 miles from 369.4 to Buckhorn Campground (Mile 394)</title><link href="http://www.barryhikesthepct.com/day-26-246-miles-from-3694-to-buckhorn-campground-mile-394.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Barry Wainstock</name></author><id>tag:www.barryhikesthepct.com,2015-05-16:day-26-246-miles-from-3694-to-buckhorn-campground-mile-394.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/kmbTkwu.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/kmbTkwu.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steve cooked us corn beef and eggs this morning and drove us to trail early.  The mountains were all covered with multiple feet of snow from the storm.  Frankenstein wasn't hiking out with us because his knee was hurting him so we all said goodbye. We were pretty bummed that we wouldn't be seeing anymore of Frankenstein.  Unfortunately, as he and Steve drove away, I realized I'd left my hat in Steve's car.  I hope I can find a hat in the next few days so I don't burn.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/2N270kk.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/2N270kk.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Because of the heavy snow, we took the High Desert Alternate Route around Mt. Baden Powell instead of going up and over. Instead of climbing 2000' over the mountain, the trail dropped 2000' below the base of the mountain and into the South Fork Campground where we ate lunch. Besides the wind, the weather was wonderful and even slightly warm.  The lower elevation here also meant no snow or wet socks.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/ghf2rsR.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/ghf2rsR.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
From lunch, we climbed back up to the base of Baden Powell over a trail made of sharp granite rocks which fell away from the mountain as we walked.  This was clearly a trail less traveled. By the top of the climb the ground was once again covered in snow and we were hiking through thick fog. 
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/P926VhF.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/P926VhF.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/ByunHKS.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/ByunHKS.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
It was about six o'clock by the time we got to the top of the trail and we still had about six miles to walk. Because it was so cold and wet we decided to jump into the back of a trail angel's truck and hitch into Buckhorn Campground. After making a fire and eating dinner we crawled into our tents to warm up and fell asleep.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Day 25 - Zero Day in Wrightwood</title><link href="http://www.barryhikesthepct.com/day-25-zero-day-in-wrightwood.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Barry Wainstock</name></author><id>tag:www.barryhikesthepct.com,2015-05-15:day-25-zero-day-in-wrightwood.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/x4aT6C4.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/x4aT6C4.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As expected, we all woke up before the rest of town and quickly ran to the local cafe.  We walked through the door just as the opened and were quickly joined by other hikers.  Our day consisted of resupplying our food bags, multiple visits to the local hardware store which acted as the hub of hiker activity, eating more food, visiting the post office, and eating a third meal somewhere between lunch and dinner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the late afternoon we called our new friend Steve to arrange dinner and he picked us up from our motel about an hour later. Steve took us back to his house and introduced us to his wonderful family: his wife Shannon and his four children, Connor, Cameron, Madison, and JB. After spending time in their lovely home and getting to know each other, we drove around the block to the family's friend's house.  We were introduced to Carlin and his family.  Carlin was a master smoker and he showed us the pork butt and ribs he was preparing.  Even Frankenstein's mouth was watering, even though he'd been a vegetarian for many years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along with the amazing smoked meats, Carlin had whipped up homemade BBQ sauce, coleslaw, mac 'n cheese, and apple pie.  To top it off, he was very generous with his whiskey cupboard and we all felt we'd died and gone to heaven.  After almost four weeks on trail, it was really great to sit around a warm home with great people and fantastic food.  Our stomachs and hearts are full of love and we're all smiling uncontrollably.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After dinner and dessert, Steve and Shannon took us back to their home and showed us to our rooms.  The kids all piled into their guest room and their rooms were lent to each of us hikers.  Steve offered to cook us breakfast tomorrow and drive us to the trail whenever we need it.  He plans to be awake fairly early so we'll hopefully get to the trail by about 7 o'clock.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Day 24 - 12.4 miles from mile 357 to Highway 2 into Wrightwood (Mile 369.4)</title><link href="http://www.barryhikesthepct.com/day-24-124-miles-from-mile-357-to-highway-2-into-wrightwood-mile-3694.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Barry Wainstock</name></author><id>tag:www.barryhikesthepct.com,2015-05-14:day-24-124-miles-from-mile-357-to-highway-2-into-wrightwood-mile-3694.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/YcBDQ9c.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/YcBDQ9c.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This morning, we woke up to cold, but sunny blue skies. The impending storm hadn't hit us yet and we were able to break camp still dry.  Town adrenaline was in our blood and we were ready to push it.  The cold helped us break camp early and quickly and we were on trail by 6:30.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/DMBkqip.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/DMBkqip.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Snow started to fall about an hour into the hike as we climbed up the ridge line.  We climbed about 1000' out of camp to the top of the mountain where the wind had really picked up.  As we climbed, the air grew colder, the wind blew harder, and we had trouble catching our breath as the altitude started to affect us.  Ice crystals were painfully whipping our faces.  Bird, Matt, and myself were all pretty miserable and had to take short breaks every few minutes.  We weren't alone in our misery though, as Junior, Happy Feet, and Colin all stopped with us along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About six miles into the hike we passed by Mountain High Ski Resort, the resort I used to snowboard at when I was younger. This unexpected landmark perked up my spirits and helped me along for the last few miles.  By noon, we reached the road where we were to hitch hike into town.  Hikers streamed out of forest onto road and waited for hitch.  About thirty minutes without seeing a car made us nervous that the road had been closed due to snow.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/Ydv4c1K.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/Ydv4c1K.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
At first, we only saw CalTrans snow plows and then a convoy of forest service volunteers.  The three cars all stopped to pick up the fourteen hikers waiting in the cold. We would later learn that the three cars ended up driving back and forth to the trailhead for the rest of the day helping out the hikers.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/LiqnCFp.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/LiqnCFp.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Our driver was gracious enough to drop us off at our motel where we met up with Frankenstein, showered, did laundry, stuffed our stomachs with delicious Mexican food, and generally lazed around. Later at night we went to the local bar and played pub trivia. We were the only hikers in the bar and ended up winning by one strategic point.  The second place team chatted with us about hiking and invited us to their home for dinner and a place to stay tomorrow.  They were extremely nice people and we are all excited for a home cooked meal and a comfortable house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow we need to run town errands, resupply our food bags, pick up my new shoes, and of course eat food.  The snow is still falling and hikers who left town yesterday have turned back.  Hikers who were stuck a day or two behind us have hitched into town and out of the bad weather.  This means town is packed and we're starting to run into friends who aren't quite on our hiking schedule.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Day 23 - 22.6 miles from mile 335.6 to 357</title><link href="http://www.barryhikesthepct.com/day-23-226-miles-from-mile-3356-to-357.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Barry Wainstock</name></author><id>tag:www.barryhikesthepct.com,2015-05-13:day-23-226-miles-from-mile-3356-to-357.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/akYsgrk.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/akYsgrk.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
An extremely lazy morning saw Matt and Frankenstein pass the campsite Bird and I stopped at last night.  They decided to head to McDonald's a bit earlier than us to get in a few extra calories before lunch.  Bird and I left camp around 8:30 and hiked a fairly easy seven miles to McDonald's.  The morning view off of the hill we were hiking down was gorgeous and the promise of air conditioning and food made us giddy.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/CJlA4Uw.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/CJlA4Uw.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
We strode into McDonald's around 10:30 and found the restaurant packed with hikers, save for a few normal people who pulled off of highway 15 to stretch their legs and get out of morning traffic.  Hashbrowns, chicken nuggets, french fries, a chocolate milkshake, and plenty of Diet Coke kept me occupied for three hours.  We all checked our email, read through the news, and chatted with the rest of the hikers about the past few weeks and the upcoming town stop in Wrightwood.  The weather forecast was calling for rain and possibly snow so the four of us booked a motel room before leaving McDonald's.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/u5SU6nx.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/u5SU6nx.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
The first few miles out of McDonald's passed through beautiful sandstone rock formations with views of train tracks winding throughout the landscape.  After this relatively flat section, we had a hard climb up towards Wrightwood.  From about 3000' near Cajon pass to 7500' with a six mile walk on a dirt road to skip a section of poisonous poodle dog bush left us pretty tired.  The calories from McDonald's got us most of the way up the mountain, but the last few miles left Bird and Matt pretty exhausted.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/MWviSBU.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/MWviSBU.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Even with a late start and a lengthy McDonald's stop, we still managed to hike 22 miles today. It was mentaly and physically challenging, but the campsite we've stopped at is worth it.  The storm that is expected looks to be coming in tomorrow morning so we plan to get an early start tomorrow and get to town as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Day 22 - 21.9 miles from mile 313.7 to 335.6</title><link href="http://www.barryhikesthepct.com/day-22-219-miles-from-mile-3137-to-3356.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-12T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Barry Wainstock</name></author><id>tag:www.barryhikesthepct.com,2015-05-12:day-22-219-miles-from-mile-3137-to-3356.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/hKvPLcb.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/hKvPLcb.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today was a fairly lazy day with relatively easy hiking.  We woke up around 5 o'clock and laid around until our regular departure time.  Leaving camp meant crossing two small streams, leading us to a short climb into the chaparral covered hills that we camped below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About two miles into the day we came across a small water cache, and more excitingly, a trash can.  We filled our water bottles, emptied our trash bags, and carried on for another four miles until second breakfast.  Frankenstein caught up with us as we were snacking and I ordered a new pair of shoes online.  Hopefully new shoes will cure the slight blister problems I've been having.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/wWo3u2i.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/wWo3u2i.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
The next few hours saw us follow the contours of the hills overlooking the flood plain below.  We stopped again for another snack break at the base of Cedar Springs Dam and waited for Frankenstein to catch us.  His knee has been giving him some serious problems, but he's powering through.  Slow and steady seems to be his mantra.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a short road walk passed a part of the California Aqueduct, Silverwood Lake came into view and we all set the beach as our goal.  A forty five minute break to dip our toes and filter water apparently wasn't long enough for us as we stopped again for another hour at a picnic site about three miles further up the trail.  We filled more water and ate lunch with Stick who was resting in the shade around the bathrooms.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/qJEA2qH.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/qJEA2qH.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
We hiked away from the lake and back into the hills until about 7 o'clock.  Our goal was to get close enough to the McDonald's near Cajon Pass that we could hit the tail end of breakfast and transition into lunch.  This meant splitting up about 10 miles out from tomorrow's goal since campsites were few and far between.  Frankenstein took the first site, Matt took the second, and Bird and I were able to find a spot just up the trail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow we'll be able to get out of camp a bit later than normal and hit McDonald's before climbing up Cajon Pass towards Wrightwood.  Hopefully we can still put in decent miles tomorrow to make Thursday relatively short.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Day 21 - 23 miles from mile 290.7 to 313.7</title><link href="http://www.barryhikesthepct.com/day-21-23-miles-from-mile-2907-to-3137.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-11T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Barry Wainstock</name></author><id>tag:www.barryhikesthepct.com,2015-05-11:day-21-23-miles-from-mile-2907-to-3137.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/MuhQmDX.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/MuhQmDX.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hike out of camp this morning was nice and easy as we followed Holcombe Creek for a bit. We climbed out of the sparsely forested boulder field into chaparral hillsides and eventually came upon Deep Creek.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We stopped for lunch here and refilled our water. Hikers slowly collected along the stream and we all excitedly discussed our plans for the hot springs later in the day. We all planned to spend multiple hours there.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/P5G454S.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/P5G454S.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
We spent about an hour and a half at the creek and worked up the energy to climb our way out passed the 300 mile marker. We followed more uncovered chaparral hillside and walked over a few wooden bridges. Eventually we found Bird resting about two miles outside of the hot springs and joined her in the shade.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/Axj3kvq.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/Axj3kvq.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
We hiked into the hot springs together and quickly got in. Multiple hot pools of various temperatures surrounded the main swimming hole. The pools were a huge hiker hangout and we spent two hours here. Finally we hiked out with Bird and Flacco up and through the canyon. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The canyon exited at the bottom of the Mojave River Forks Dam. We had to cross the last trickles of Deep Creek to find flat ground for camp. Frankenstein joined us and we all ate dinner together before falling asleep. Big miles and multiple long breaks left us all exhausted.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Day 20 - 24.2 miles from mile 266 to 290.2</title><link href="http://www.barryhikesthepct.com/day-20-242-miles-from-mile-266-to-2902.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Barry Wainstock</name></author><id>tag:www.barryhikesthepct.com,2015-05-10:day-20-242-miles-from-mile-266-to-2902.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/z65yKEZ.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/z65yKEZ.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all woke up early enough this morning to make coffee and pancakes in the hostel kitchen before the hostel shuttle took us to the trailhead. Along with Bird and Frankenstein, El Flacco and Ram joined us on the ride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a short climb from the road the trail felt flat and the weather was cool and breezy. We hiked above and around Big Bear Lake with the snow dusted San Bernardino Mountains in the background. Day hikers were out and about on the trails and we were all pretty envious of their small packs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the pine forest around Big Bear we transitioned into a burnt matchstick landscape. The hillsides were all charred and barren after fires from recent years. If this wasn't a relatively cool weather year, this section would be brutally hot with nowhere to hide in the shade.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/DZv7M9J.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/DZv7M9J.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
The trail wound around the edge of the valley with the burnt hills surrounding us. We eventually dropped into the boulder studded valley and we walked through the center of the valley for a few miles. By 3 o'clock we had hiked 20 miles and took a break to eat and rest. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My knee was tightening up and in pain so we decided to walk four more miles and call it a night. El Flacco had already setup camp and we joined him for dinner and stories in a beautiful open campsite. We all watched the sunset and the stars come out as Flacco told us fun stories of the Appalachian Trail. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow we'll hike another 20 or so miles with Wrightwood in our sights by Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Day 19 - Zero Day in Big Bear</title><link href="http://www.barryhikesthepct.com/day-19-zero-day-in-big-bear.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Barry Wainstock</name></author><id>tag:www.barryhikesthepct.com,2015-05-09:day-19-zero-day-in-big-bear.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Our hiker hunger woke us up fairly early this morning and, along with Bird, we stumbled over to the Teddy Bear Cafe for breakfast. After eating enough food for six, we wandered through town back to the hostel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After I called my cousin Debi to setup lunch, Bird and I lounged on the living room couch and watched the rest of the hikers wake while Matt called his girlfriend, Cassie. Around noon, Debi and Bob picked Matt and me up and we headed to Sizzler. All you can eat sounded perfect for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bob and Debi graciously offered to follow us around the market while we resupplied our food and dropped us back off at the hostel. After a quick run to the sporting goods store for fuel, we ran back to the hostel to catch the new Avengers movie with Bird and Frankenstein. As is typical, we went out to eat after.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our names are on the 7:30 shuttle list back to the trail so we've called it an early night. Big Bear was a great town to zero in and we feel pretty good about putting in big miles tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Day 18 - 15.5 miles from 250.5 to Big Bear City (Mile 266)</title><link href="http://www.barryhikesthepct.com/day-18-155-miles-from-2505-to-big-bear-city-mile-266.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-08T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Barry Wainstock</name></author><id>tag:www.barryhikesthepct.com,2015-05-08:day-18-155-miles-from-2505-to-big-bear-city-mile-266.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/odsqx8R.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/odsqx8R.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rain that was expected last night never showed up, but we did wake up to about half an inch of snow. I was pretty impressed and really enjoyed the scenery. Despite the cold and the still falling flurries, we still made good time out of camp.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/SOv9sHg.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/SOv9sHg.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
The day was relatively easy hiking as we gradually dropped from 8300 ft to 7000 over 15.5 miles. By 10 o'clock, the snow had stopped falling and the sun fought through the clouds to warm us up. We passed by a cooler full of soda and candy around mile 252 which really lifted our spirits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The day hiking into town usually revolves around thoughts of food, a bed, and showers. Town adrenaline and cold winds meant we didn't take very many breaks. I've also decided I don't like most of the food I've packed so I tried my best not to eat lunch on the trail today. That's something I really need to figure out quickly.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/xu6RpRn.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/xu6RpRn.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Around 1:30 we reached highway 18 and picked up a hitch into town. A quick stop at the post office and another hitch to the hostel meant little time running errands. Thankfully Bird had saved us a spot at the hostel because the snow meant a lot of hikers were bunkering down for the night. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hung around the hostel as hikers streamed in through the day and we filled the time with food as always. Tomorrow we'll resupply and regenerate. I hope to meet my cousin Debi for lunch and the rest of the day is for lounging around. Sunday we'll leave big Bear with Wrightwood in our sights.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Day 17 - 18.3 miles from 232.2 to 250.5</title><link href="http://www.barryhikesthepct.com/day-17-183-miles-from-2322-to-2505.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-07T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Barry Wainstock</name></author><id>tag:www.barryhikesthepct.com,2015-05-07:day-17-183-miles-from-2322-to-2505.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/NChxlBG.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/NChxlBG.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As is normal, we were out of camp this morning around seven and had a big club ahead of us. Up and out of the desert creek around 4000 ft, we climbed until mile 248 to 8700 ft. It was hard, but it felt good to get some physical hiking in. A lot of the trail has been pretty flat or gradual and we were able to really feel the burn here.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/fKjVvIO.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/fKjVvIO.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
I started the day really strong. Mentally and physically I was feeling good and the climbs were great. Climbing into the crisp air of the mountains felt great and reminded me of Thanksgiving in Arrowhead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After eating lunch at mile 242, we continued our ascent to the top of the San Bernardino Mountains and walked along the edge looking back across the valley at San Jacinto Peak. I was drained for the last six miles and should have been eating more food.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/Yw44CTo.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/Yw44CTo.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
By five o'clock we were exhausted and picked a flat spot to camp nestled in a little canyon. The wispy clouds coming over the surrounding ridges whirlpool together right above our heads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The weather report is calling for rain tonight and tomorrow with a chance of snow. We only have 16 miles to go to get to Big Bear so we should be fine.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Day 16 - 21.4 miles from 210.8 to 232.2</title><link href="http://www.barryhikesthepct.com/day-16-214-miles-from-2108-to-2322.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Barry Wainstock</name></author><id>tag:www.barryhikesthepct.com,2015-05-06:day-16-214-miles-from-2108-to-2322.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;  
  &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/LANecjj.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/LANecjj.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wind last night at the trail angel house was outrageous. The tarps that were setup to cover the hikers shook all night and I probably got my worst night of sleep yet. We finally got up with all is the other hikers around 5:30 and ate our left over pizza. By 7 o'clock we had packed and said goodbye and started our 1500 ft climb out of the Coachella Valley.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/q3rjLkd.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/q3rjLkd.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
The temperature was mild, but the wind was still screaming. We walked along a grassy ridge for a bit and finally descended into Whitewater Preserve. This area used to be trout farm and is now a nature preserve with a fantastic ranger station offering camping and water. We wished we had camped here instead of Ziggy and the Bear. 
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/SWSCsoJ.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/SWSCsoJ.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
After taking a break here and refilling our water, we climbed about 3000 ft and followed more exposed grassy ridges. The heat had finally picked up and the day dragged.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/AQaxE6N.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/AQaxE6N.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Just when we were about done with the ridge and the heat, we dropped down to Mission Creek and followed along until camp. We found Pia, who now goes by Bird, Frankenstein, and Lucas already at the campsite and decided it was a good time to stop.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/jaTqPXe.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/jaTqPXe.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Tomorrow we start a pretty major climb into the San Bernardino Mountains on our way to Big Bear.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Day 15 - 20.3 miles from 190.5 to Ziggy and the Bear (Mile 210.8)</title><link href="http://www.barryhikesthepct.com/day-15-203-miles-from-1905-to-ziggy-and-the-bear-mile-2108.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Barry Wainstock</name></author><id>tag:www.barryhikesthepct.com,2015-05-05:day-15-203-miles-from-1905-to-ziggy-and-the-bear-mile-2108.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/slXBH0l.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/slXBH0l.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This morning was our coldest morning yet. We expected that as we camped around 8000 feet, but it was still impressive just how cold it was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After warming up in the few rays of sun peering through the trees, we descended down Snow Creek Canyon on our way to the desert floor at 1100 feet. When we reached 6300 feet the pine trees and squirrels turned back into desert chaparral and lizards. The trail was washed out in parts and was covered in fist sized rocks. Hiking was mentally intensive and we really had to pay attention to our footsteps.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/T937sKA.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/T937sKA.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Even though the trail was basically a series of switchbacks, one after another for twenty miles, the views were awesome. Out in front of us was the Coachella Valley with views of Morongo Casino and the Mesa Wind Farm. Behind us loomed the snow speckled San Jacinto Peak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around 2 o'clock we reached the bottom of the mountain and refilled our water. The last five miles took us across the valley and under Interstate 80. The wind whipping through the valley made this portion of the hike incredibly frustrating and the coarse sand didn't help ease the pain.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/epE91lR.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/epE91lR.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
By five o'clock we reached the trail angel house that Ziggy and the Bear run where they offer showers, basic resupply, and covered sleeping areas. After the day's hiking, the Little Caesars pizza they picked up tasted amazing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like all of the other hiker hangouts, we enjoyed seeing everyone wander in throughout the evening and traded hiker stories. Tomorrow we'll start our climb through the San Bernardino Mountains on our way to Big Bear.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Day 14 - 9.6 miles from Devil's Slide Trail to campsite at 190.5</title><link href="http://www.barryhikesthepct.com/day-14-96-miles-from-devils-slide-trail-to-campsite-at-1905.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-04T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Barry Wainstock</name></author><id>tag:www.barryhikesthepct.com,2015-05-04:day-14-96-miles-from-devils-slide-trail-to-campsite-at-1905.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/Dt0wUGE.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/Dt0wUGE.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we needed to finish up a few errands and make our way out of town. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After eating breakfast at the delicious Red Kettle with Pia and 12%, we picked up a few packages that we had waiting for us at the post office. Matt's girlfriend, Cassie, sent us homemade cookies and a few dehydrated dinners which was awesome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To supplement the cookies we picked up a few other things at the local market and checked out of our hotel. After saying goodbye to all of the hikers sticking around for a bit longer, we hitched to the bottom of Devil's Slide Trail and started hiking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Devil's Slide Trail isn't part of the PCT, but it's the way of out Idyllwild. It's also the steepest trail we've climbed so far, gaining a bit under 2000 feet in about 2.5 miles. The trail connects to the PCT at around 9000 feet in beautiful pine forest. Our plan was to follow the trail to San Jacinto Peak and climb up to 10800 ft, but the sky was looking quite dark and a few rain drops had begun to fall.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/3GNtgG8.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/3GNtgG8.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
We decided to skip the peak and continued to mile 186 to fill our water at a creek fed by snow melt. We'd already seen a few left over snow patches and now we were drinking ice cold snow melt.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/j1527R7.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/j1527R7.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Off to the north of the mountain we could see Cabazon, Morongo Casino, and the Mesa Wind Farm down at 1200 feet. By 7:30 we hit camp and ended the night with Velcro, Sebaba, Spider, and a number of other hikers.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/CuRhb9r.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/CuRhb9r.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Tomorrow we'll hike 20 miles down to the desert floor and over to the trail angel house Ziggy and the Bear. We'll also pass the 200 mile mark which feels like a pretty major accomplishment.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Day 13 - Zero Day in Idyllwild</title><link href="http://www.barryhikesthepct.com/day-13-zero-day-in-idyllwild.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Barry Wainstock</name></author><id>tag:www.barryhikesthepct.com,2015-05-03:day-13-zero-day-in-idyllwild.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/3JxMnwz.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/3JxMnwz.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last night we slept on the lawn of the Paradise Valley Cafe. This meant breakfast was only a few steps away. After wolfing down a huge breakfast burrito, Matt and I wandered over to the highway and stuck our thumbs out for a hitch. After only a few minutes, Blake from Temecula picked us and gave us a tour of Idyllwild. He was visiting his mother for the weekend and invited us over for drinks. Unfortunately we had too many errands to run and thanked him for the ride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The day mostly consisted of resting in our hotel room, hanging out with other hikers, and eating. Because it was a weekend, Idyllwild was swarming with people. Hikers and bikers and Am Diego tourists were everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At night we went out to dinner with a group of hikers including Hands, Pandora, Salt Lick, Purple Princess, and a few others. Tomorrow we'll get to the post office to pick up some resupply packages, top off our food bag at the market, and climb Devil's Slide Trail out of town.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Day 12 - 15.2 miles from mile 136.5 to Paradise Valley Cafe (Mile 151.7)</title><link href="http://www.barryhikesthepct.com/day-12-152-miles-from-mile-1365-to-paradise-valley-cafe-mile-1517.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Barry Wainstock</name></author><id>tag:www.barryhikesthepct.com,2015-05-02:day-12-152-miles-from-mile-1365-to-paradise-valley-cafe-mile-1517.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/RnBrCjC.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/RnBrCjC.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trend of early mornings continues. This is probably the norm now. By the time we got out of camp around 7 it must have already been 80 degrees. It was hot! Our water source was a half mile from camp and then we started our ascent.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/AqhtiP6.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/AqhtiP6.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
By 11 o'clock we were getting hungry and started to look for a shady spot to rest. In the distance we saw a large tent setup and we decided to investigate. It was more trail magic! Mary from Anza was getting ready to grill hamburgers, hotdogs, and marinated pork loin. She also had ice cold water, juice, and soda. This was hiker heaven. Our short break once again turned into a multi hour stop as 12%, the Beaverton Brothers, and a lot more hikers streamed in.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/kkrILGa.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/kkrILGa.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
The last eight miles flew by as we climbed our way to Highway 78 where we planned to hitchhike to the Paradise Valley Cafe. Mike from Anza quickly picked us up. Mike was a kindergarten teacher and had a very small apple orchard at his home. After hearing that we were PCT hikers , he offered us a stay at his house complete with home-cooked meal, showers, and laundry. Unfortunately, Matt didn't feel comfortable taking the offer and we just had Mike take us to the restaurant. 
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/CdJWrzF.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/CdJWrzF.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
We both got giant burgers and ate dinner with Purple Princess and Hoat. Paradise Valley Cafe lets hikers camp on their property so we stayed the night and plan to hitch into Idyllwild after breakfast tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Day 11 - 17 miles from mile 119.5 to a campsite at mile 136.5</title><link href="http://www.barryhikesthepct.com/day-11-17-miles-from-mile-1195-to-a-campsite-at-mile-1365.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Barry Wainstock</name></author><id>tag:www.barryhikesthepct.com,2015-05-01:day-11-17-miles-from-mile-1195-to-a-campsite-at-mile-1365.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/DLFOqZz.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/DLFOqZz.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plan for the day was to hike eight miles to our next water source and then nine more miles to camp. We're still taking our time so we got out of camp early and really watched our pace.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/Pb1sAgg.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/Pb1sAgg.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Our water for the day was supposed to come from a water tank near a trail angel's house. When we got there, it turns out the house not only had water, but food, beer, shade, and a pretty awesome trail angel host. Mike Herrera runs a desert hiker oasis and allows hikers to camp in his yard. Our 30 minute water break turned into a three hour siesta and it was amazing. Thanks Mike!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After our midday nap, we hopped back on trail and descended 2000 feet to mile 136.5 by 8:45. Tonight is the first night we are camping by ourselves which is pretty amazing.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/IQHveeq.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/IQHveeq.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Tomorrow we will get to mile 151 and the trail famous Paradise Valley Cafe. We'll stay the night on the restaurant's lawn and then hitchhike into Idyllwild. Most years you can hike into Idyllwild, but a recent fire along the trail has forced an alternate route along the highway. This didn't sound appealing to us so we'll hitch into town and stay the night.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Day 10 - 10 miles from Warner Springs Resource Center to campsite at mile 119.5</title><link href="http://www.barryhikesthepct.com/day-10-10-miles-from-warner-springs-resource-center-to-campsite-at-mile-1195.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-04-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Barry Wainstock</name></author><id>tag:www.barryhikesthepct.com,2015-04-30:day-10-10-miles-from-warner-springs-resource-center-to-campsite-at-mile-1195.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/l9anPfq.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/l9anPfq.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We weren't planning on going too far today so we waited out the heat and planned to leave Warner Springs later in the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pretzel was still hanging around and Pia came back from spending the night at a trail angel's house to spend time with the other hikers. At some point Twelve Percent showed up and shared his stories about finding a trail wife. That guy is a character, that's for sure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around 4 o'clock we said goodbye to everyone and set off. We slowly hiked through the grassy fields surrounding Warner Springs and followed Agua Caliente Creek for a few miles. Around 7:30 we stopped for dinner and put our headlamps on. We still wanted to fit a few more miles in, but it was getting dark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By 9:30 we reached mile 119.5 and called it quits. We quietly setup camp near a few other tents and drifted off to sleep. Further up the trail you could see headlamps bopping up and down we could hear voices off in the distance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The slower pace of the day left my knee feeling pretty good. We'll continue to mosey our way towards mile 151 where we can hitch into Idyllwild. We're planning to take a precautionary zero day there.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Day 9 - Zero Day In Warner Springs</title><link href="http://www.barryhikesthepct.com/day-9-zero-day-in-warner-springs.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-04-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Barry Wainstock</name></author><id>tag:www.barryhikesthepct.com,2015-04-29:day-9-zero-day-in-warner-springs.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/ASpp4B0.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title="Pia, Me, and Big Spoon cook up burgers for the masses."&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/ASpp4B0.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;div class="image-caption"&gt;
        Pia, Me, and Big Spoon cook up burgers for the masses.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slowly but surely the campground woke up starting at 6 o'clock. Some of the hikers were getting an early start while others were waiting for the Resource Center to open for breakfast. At 8 o'clock, the volunteers arrived and announced that they couldn't serve food because they were having permit issues. Apparently a community member called in a complaint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was pretty deflating and most of the hikers not zeroing left soon after. Those of us that were zeroing just hung around and relaxed. We enjoyed the air-conditioned Resource Center with Honey Stick, Anna, and Pia as we all soaked our feet and traded hiking stories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;City inspectors were in and out all day and it seemed like things weren't looking good. Their kitchen had been okayed by the county, but their permit was not current. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slowly through the day the previous day's hikers were replaced with new ones. It was sad to see the people we'd been hiking with for the past week leave, but it was fun to meet a whole new group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since there was no hot food being served, we asked if we could buy the frozen hamburgers and fixings and grill it on the charcoal bbq outside the Center. For whatever reason, they are okay with this and we jumped into action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sinatra and friends hitched to the store and bought charcoal. Pia jumped on the grill and I worked on gathering all of the food.  Big Spoon quickly joined to help and we started a hamburger list. Just about the whole campground signed up and we cooked up 36 burgers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After cleanup, I was exhausted and laid low with Pretzel and Malibu. 8 o'clock rolled around, aka Hiker Midnight, and everyone naturally went to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow we'll take a nearo and hike about ten miles in the afternoon. My knee is starting to feel better and the swelling is going down in Matt's leg.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Day 8 - 15 miles from a campsite at mile 94.5 to Warner Springs Resource Center (Mile 109.5)</title><link href="http://www.barryhikesthepct.com/day-8-15-miles-from-a-campsite-at-mile-945-to-warner-springs-resource-center-mile-1095.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-04-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Barry Wainstock</name></author><id>tag:www.barryhikesthepct.com,2015-04-28:day-8-15-miles-from-a-campsite-at-mile-945-to-warner-springs-resource-center-mile-1095.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/qOaBnoF.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/qOaBnoF.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whole time I've been on trail there has been a lot of aircraft activity. We saw  Border Patrol helicopters in the first few days, San Diego Airport flight paths, and plenty of military jets from nearby bases. Last night added military helicopter squadrons with six in the first pass and five in the second. It's fun to see, but not great when it's the middle of the night.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/KHOj8In.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/KHOj8In.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Other than that, we were up by 5 and out of camp by 6 hoping to beat the heat. It was already warm. We climbed down the mountain passing the 100 mile mark and into Barrel Springs at mile 101 to fill our water. It was almost like being back at home with oak trees, yellow grass, and even poison oak. There were hikers camped out all over and plenty of people just waiting out the heat.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/wxQ84Jt.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/wxQ84Jt.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
After a short break, we hiked out into rolling grassland hills towards Eagle Rock.  My knee was really sore and I was having a lot of trouble with this section. While taking a breather under an oak tree, Starfish showed up and we hiked with her for a bit. We all took pictures at Eagle Rock which was way cooler than I expected. The last mile brought us into the Warner Springs Resource Center.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/jcEBlD3.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/jcEBlD3.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
This small community center is amazing. The women that work here offer hot food, laundry services, showers, camping, and so much more. We ate, showered, staked a claim on the grass, and picked up our food resupply from the post office. By the end of the night there were probably 40 hikers.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/r0426bx.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/r0426bx.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Tomorrow we have decided to take a zero day. My knee is extremely sore and Matt's shin is still swollen. Hopefully some rest will help us both.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Day 7 - 17.5 miles from Scissor's Crossing to a patch of dirt at mile 94.5</title><link href="http://www.barryhikesthepct.com/day-7-175-miles-from-scissors-crossing-to-a-patch-of-dirt-at-mile-945.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-04-27T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Barry Wainstock</name></author><id>tag:www.barryhikesthepct.com,2015-04-27:day-7-175-miles-from-scissors-crossing-to-a-patch-of-dirt-at-mile-945.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/Ufap3Cz.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/Ufap3Cz.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today was supposed to be a hot day and uncovered for most of the way so we decided to get out of camp as early as possible. By 7 o'clock we were packed up and out of camp. We walked down the road back the trailhead with Starfish and eventually got a hitch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we got to the trail, a trail angel was handing out fresh fruit and Cactus Cooler which made the already scorching heat a bit more bearable.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/KbF1sLB.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/KbF1sLB.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Our hike started with a climb over the first few miles and then flattened out for the rest of the time. Yucca and cactus dominated the landscape the whole time. Once the trail flattened out, the day was a trudge. We followed the contours of the mountain for about 15 miles. In and out, in and out, but always in direct sunlight.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/h7XJwTe.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/h7XJwTe.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
At mile 91 we hit the Third Gate water cache. Because there was no running water, someone had brought about 50 gallons of water out to the middle of nowhere. This became a natural stopping point for everyone and there were hikers taking a break all over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a two hour siesta to wait out the midday sun, we headed out to finish the last three miles of our day. We finished our hike at mile 94.5 and setup camp by 6 o'clock. A hiker named Mad Science was already in camp and we watched as Honey Stick, Diogenes, and a few others trickled in. Tomorrow we want to get started even earlier so we're hoping to get to bed early tonight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My knee is still really bothering me and Matt's shin is severely swollen. We think I've got an IT band problem and he's got bad shin splints. Tomorrow will be a slow hobble into the Warner Springs Resource Center where we'll be able to get a hot meal and camp for free. &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Day 6 - 18 miles from Sunshine Trailhead to Scissor's Crossing (Mile 77)</title><link href="http://www.barryhikesthepct.com/day-6-18-miles-from-sunshine-trailhead-to-scissors-crossing-mile-77.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-04-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Barry Wainstock</name></author><id>tag:www.barryhikesthepct.com,2015-04-26:day-6-18-miles-from-sunshine-trailhead-to-scissors-crossing-mile-77.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As soon as our eyes opened this morning and we saw sunshine, we knew today was going to be a good day. After packing up and eating breakfast, we walked down to the highway to hitchhike back to the trail. After only a few minutes, a local piemaker picked us up and took us straight to be 
Sunshine Trailhead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The parking lot looked completely different compared to the last time we were here. We could actually see! The first nine miles flew by as we enjoyed the sunshine and cool breeze. The view we had expected on Friday was finally visible and it didn't disappoint. We could see all the way to the desert floor. We were slowly dropping about 1500 feet and would eventually hit the valley below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We stopped for lunch and refilled our water at mile 68. A number of other hikers were hanging around the precious water and we chatted about gear and the weather. Over the next nine miles, we would run into Silver, Two Watches, Dugan, and Sarah again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After we finally reached the bottom of the mountain, we only had a few more miles until the road we planned to hitchhike on. The rocky chaparral of the mountainside became cactus and yucca as far as the eye could see. We met another hiker named Starfish and walked the last hundred yards to the road together. We invited her to come with us to the RV park, but she decided to try her luck the other direction on thth road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matt and I stuck our thumbs out and started walking. Our campsite was only about four miles away, but someone was bound to drive by and pick us up. After about ten cars and not even a hint of a bite, we just resigned ourselves to walking. That is until a state park ranger pulled up with Starfish in his car and offered us a ride. Finally!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're now camped at a slightly strange RV park in the middle of the desert. We found Silver, Dugan, and Sarah already setting up camp when we arrived and Two Watches showed up later in the evening. The desert sky is gorgeous at night and the wind is pretty calm. I'm looking forward to sleep tonight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our goal for tomorrow is mile 94.5 with a potential walk back to the trail, so another twenty mile day is ahead of us. Then on Tuesday we head into the tiny town of Warner Springs to pickup our first resupply box.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Day 5 - Zero Day in Julian</title><link href="http://www.barryhikesthepct.com/day-5-zero-day-in-julian.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-04-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Barry Wainstock</name></author><id>tag:www.barryhikesthepct.com,2015-04-25:day-5-zero-day-in-julian.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;After checking the weather report we decided to take today off, known on the trail as a zero day. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We spent the day alternating eating, stretching, and sleeping. Julian is a very cute historical town and I'd love to come back on a nice weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The storm is supposed to blow out tonight and we are planning on hitchhiking back to Sunrise Trailhead tomorrow morning. Our goal is to hike 18 miles and hitch four miles to a nearby RV park.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Day 4 - 17 miles from Mt. Laguna to Sunrise Trailhead (Mile 59.7)</title><link href="http://www.barryhikesthepct.com/day-4-17-miles-from-mt-laguna-to-sunrise-trailhead-mile-597.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-04-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Barry Wainstock</name></author><id>tag:www.barryhikesthepct.com,2015-04-24:day-4-17-miles-from-mt-laguna-to-sunrise-trailhead-mile-597.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/MXxhI9E.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/MXxhI9E.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today was intense and ended much better than it started. After 17 miles of crazy stormy hiking, we were holed up in a trailhead bathroom with another hiker named Kenny. It was 4:30 in the afternoon and our plan was to sleep in the 10 sqft bathroom. The storm wasn't letting up anytime soon and it was going to be a long night.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/l4YSN6B" data-lightbox="images" data-title="We could only stop to catch our breath when the wind was quiet."&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/l4YSN6B"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;div class="image-caption"&gt;
        We could only stop to catch our breath when the wind was quiet.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Around 5:30 a man named Paint Your Wagon appeared and offered us a ride to Lake Morena. He was just driving by and figured he'd check and see if anyone was hiding in the bathroom. We told him we were headed the other way and he bid us good luck. Before driving away, Paint Your Wagon poked his head back in and tossed us a bag of homemade muffins. His positivity was really awesome as more and more water was starting to leak into our temporary home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By 6:30, the floor was pretty much completely wet and we were all a bit nervous about the next twelve hours. Just as we were going over midnight toilet etiquette, Keith from the Laguna Mountain Store showed up. He was also just driving by and figured he'd check in. Apparently this was a well known hideaway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike Paint Your Wagon, Keith offered us a ride to Julian, a small town up the road with a lodge. With a knowing look at each other, Matt and I took him up on his offer. Between the unrelenting weather, the unsanitary bathroom, and our growing aches, a warm dry room sounded great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We said goodbye to Kenny and quickly hopped in Keith's truck. We pulled into town and he dropped us off in front of a cafe. We thanked him profusely and ducked in for some soup and tea. A quick phone call to the Julian Lodge and we booked ourselves a small room. We felt that we could justify this after the day we'd had.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The morning started as we filled our emptied bags back to capacity and made our way out of Mt. Laguna by 8:30. The mist that rolled in last night had stuck around which made for a chilly start. Amazingly, this was the calm before the storm.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/q9yXvwd.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/q9yXvwd.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
The trail very slowly descended 1000 feet over the 17 miles we hiked while overooking the floor of the Colorado Desert. Or so we've seen in pictures. Over the 17 miles, the morning mist turned into whipping rain and 40 mph gusting wind. At the best times, we could see 150 feet in front of us. At the worst, five.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our first stop of the day was at a trailhead six miles out to fill our water bottles. We saw two hikers who we had met in town, Comet and Not A Bear. People tend to go by fun names out here. We didn't stick around long as the temperature was dropping and we needed to warm back up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of our hike today was a trudge and there wasn't much to look at. Every so often, the silhouette of a mountain or a boulder would appear and just as quickly vanish. We could hear voices in the distance, but we couldn't be sure it wasn't just the wind howling. 
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/h6qTzpP.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/h6qTzpP.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
At our second water stop around noon we learned that the voices belonged to a group of hikers who met on the Appalachian Trail last year. Karate Kid, Forest, Sass, and Popeye joined us for lunch and we traded weather complaints. 
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/s0iWeCM.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/s0iWeCM.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
We filled our water from a water cache here. Amazing people referred to as trail angels bring gallon jugs of water to parts of the trail that might not have other sources. Sometimes they are former hikers and sometimes they're just caring communities members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Four hours of extreme marching later and we ran into Kenny. If you've read this far, you know the rest. We are so grateful for the support and encouragement from complete strangers. Tomorrow is unplanned in case the storm keeps going. We'll have to wait and see.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Day 3 - 10 miles from Fred Canyon to Mt. Laguna (Mile 42.3)</title><link href="http://www.barryhikesthepct.com/day-3-10-miles-from-fred-canyon-to-mt-laguna-mile-423.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-04-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Barry Wainstock</name></author><id>tag:www.barryhikesthepct.com,2015-04-23:day-3-10-miles-from-fred-canyon-to-mt-laguna-mile-423.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/jKTBtBH.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=" Around mile 40 the high desert gave way to pine forest and we see our first tree marker."&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/jKTBtBH.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;div class="image-caption"&gt;
        Around mile 40 the high desert gave way to pine forest and we see our first tree marker.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We woke this morning to the sound of birds chirping all around us. This seemed to be the natural alarm for everyone because the other three hikers were stirring too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We wasted no time in breaking camp and were out by 8 o'clock. We didn't have far to go, but we wanted to be able to stop into the small market in town before they closed.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/XyHv77U.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/XyHv77U.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/HAT0qz9.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/HAT0qz9.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Once again the day was fairly cool and we were able to keep a good pace with only three liters of water. My knee was feeling better and my energy level felt good. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hike into town was almost completely uphill, but it wasn't too bad. The scenery was gorgeous and once we climbed high enough, the high desert landscape turned into low mountain. Pine trees and wildflowers came into view and really brightened our day.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/YZWzrUX.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/YZWzrUX.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
We came into town around noon and walked straight to the motel. A shower and a bed sounded amazing, especially because the campground cost almost as much. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a stop into the local cafe and outfitters, we picked up food for the next five days and planned our hike into Warner Springs. It looks like there is a 30+ mile stretch without water that we'll have to deal with. 
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/wGpVS0w.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/wGpVS0w.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
A good night's rest in even a cheap motel bed sounds amazing. Tomorrow we have 17 miles until our camp site.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Day 2 - 12 Miles from Lake Morena to Fred Canyon (Mile 32)</title><link href="http://www.barryhikesthepct.com/day-2-12-miles-from-lake-morena-to-fred-canyon-mile-32.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-04-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Barry Wainstock</name></author><id>tag:www.barryhikesthepct.com,2015-04-22:day-2-12-miles-from-lake-morena-to-fred-canyon-mile-32.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/stQiVV1.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/stQiVV1.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were able to casually wake up and "lounge" around this morning since we had to wait until noon for the kickoff event tot start.  We were even able to walk about a quarter mile down the road and eat breakfast at the Lake Morena Malt Shop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some deliciously basic eggs and toast, we found the kickoff event posted the schedule for the day. Unfortunately, it turns out today was pretty light on talks and was mostly registration and dinner. We picked up a PCT 2015 bandana, checked out some of the vendors, and decided to hit the trail. All in all, kind of disappointing.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/UI6tB3b.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/UI6tB3b.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
We got out of Lake Morena at about 2 o'clock and figured we could hike about twelve miles before sundown. This would leave us with a relatively mild ten mile hike tomorrow to get to our first town, Mt. Laguna.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first two miles skirted the lake and went through very coarse sand which was frustrating. Eventually, we dipped under a road and followed along for the next few hours.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/JnOR6Cf.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/JnOR6Cf.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
By four o'clock we passed through a horse campground where we refilled our water. Seven more miles up around a mountain took us to our campsite at Fred Canyon where we found three other hikers getting ready for bed. We quickly setup camp and ate dinner.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/9TsN1V2.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/9TsN1V2.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
My legs are sore and my right knee hurts more than I'd like.  The shorter hike tomorrow is welcome and we'll resupply and camp in town.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Day One - Mexican Border to Lake Morena</title><link href="http://www.barryhikesthepct.com/day-one-mexican-border-to-lake-morena.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-04-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Barry Wainstock</name></author><id>tag:www.barryhikesthepct.com,2015-04-21:day-one-mexican-border-to-lake-morena.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/Tukshlb.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title="We were so surprised with how green this part of the desert is!"&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/Tukshlb.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;div class="image-caption"&gt;
        We were so surprised with how green this part of the desert is!
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day 1 is officially in the books. We made it the full 19.8 miles to Lake Morena and were able to setup camp with plenty of light to spare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our hike started at about ten past nine when Matt's girlfriend Cassie dropped is off at the trailhead.  Thete were two other hikers taking pictures at the monument with us, Kerby and Carlene. We said our goodbyes and headed out.  That was the last we'd see of those two hikers for the day.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/D5kIC0a.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title="Leaving the trailhead"&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/D5kIC0a.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;div class="image-caption"&gt;
        Leaving the trailhead
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Thankfully, it was fairly overcast until about noon and the day stayed fairly cool. The wildflowers were in bloom and the trail was much more colorful than I expected.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/IsBR7Cy.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title="So many wildflowers"&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/IsBR7Cy.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;div class="image-caption"&gt;
        So many wildflowers
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Along the way, we must have passed about 15 other hikers. Apparently this is a lot and we shouldn't expect that further on. It was nice knowing there were other people within walking distance and i might be sad to lose that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We walked up to or original stopping point around 4 and felt good enough to walk the five miles to Lake Morena. These last miles took us up the steepest climb of the day which turned out to be pretty mild compared to some of our training hikes. By 6 we had reached the campground and found a spot to setup near a group of other hikers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are about 20 of us total tonight with hundreds more expected over the next few days for the kickoff event. The big talk of the event is the water report people are talking about multiple thirty plus mile stretches without water sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow we'll stick around for the event and try to hike an easy ten miles to our next campsite. There are two water sources within those miles which thankfully allows us to carry only a few pounds of water.  Overall, the day felt great. Hopefully there are no weird aches in the morning.
&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/GzLzUKA.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/GzLzUKA.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;div class="image-caption"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>It All Starts Tomorrow</title><link href="http://www.barryhikesthepct.com/it-all-starts-tomorrow.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-04-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Barry Wainstock</name></author><id>tag:www.barryhikesthepct.com,2015-04-20:it-all-starts-tomorrow.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="post-image"&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://i.imgur.com/bk2FHj4.jpg" data-lightbox="images" data-title=""&gt;
        &lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/bk2FHj4.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, the past year of training and planning is finally coming to fruition. At about 8AM, Matt and I will show up at the PCT trailhead and start off on our 2,660 mile hike. I find it's easier to wrap my head around this whole thing if I think about it as a series of smaller hikes, so this is really just a three day backpacking trip to Mount Laguna. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This first leg has us starting off fairly slowly and taking three days to walk the 42.6 miles to Mount Laguna. Reports from the trail say that the desert temperature is fairly tolerable right now, so we might be able to do this in two days. I think we'll quickly find that a plan is good to have and even better to throw away. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest challenge throughout the desert will be water.  There is no reliable water on trail in the first 20 or so miles, so we'll make sure to hydrate well tonight and carry about six liters with us tomorrow. This will get us to the Lake Morena campground where the annual PCT kickoff event starts on Wednesday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The kickoff event happens every year and offers hikers a number of useful resources. Veteran hikers will give presentations and seminars on trail topics, vendors will be on site to help fit and sell gear, and other volunteers will be around for general tips and tricks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We stuffed our bags full of food and triple checked that we haven't forgotten any essentials. The only things left to do are get some sleep and start hiking. &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry></feed>